A Guide to the Colonial Papers, 1630-1778
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Colonial Papers, 1630-1778
The Library of Virginia
36138
3 cubic feet.
Virginia (Colony)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Acquired prior to 1905.
Alternative Form Available
Also available on microfilm (Miscellaneous Reels 609-612).
Historical Information
The history of Virginia's colonial government is divided into two significant phases by the date of May 24, 1624, when the charter of the Virginia Company of London was revoked by the crown. Prior to that date the colony had been run as a private corporation with final authority resting in the hands of the stockholders; afterwards, it was a royal colony with all the trappings and institutions of government that such a status required. The Grand Assembly, begun in 1619, evolved into the House of Burgesses by 1642, governors and lieutenant governors were sent to the colony as the king's viceroys, regular courts were established, and a complex system of government was developed to lead and protect the growing colony.
Scope and Content
The Colonial Papers are arranged in two series. series have been designated for Chronological Files and Petitions to the House of Burgesses. The Colonial Papers contain a collection of loose papers more closely connected by age than by any other single factor that consist largely of records kept by the clerk of the colonial council, House of Burgesses, the governor and other officials, relating to county as well as colony-wide government. The records of the colonial government have, for the most part, been destroyed by wars, fires, and early neglect. This collection of loose colonial papers is arranged in chronological order, in fifty-three folders. The collection consists of petitions to the governor or House of Burgesses, court records, orders, summonses, patents, accounts, proceedings, returns, grants, proclamations, addresses, certificates and correspondence.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Chronological Files, 1630-1778
Series II: Petitions to the House of Burgesses, 1774-1775
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
Palmer, W.P. ed. Calendar of Virginia State Papers: and other manuscripts preserved in the Capitol at Richmond, v. 1, 1652-1781 (Richmond: 1875).
Separated Material
Oversized material has been separated to Box 151 and Oversized Drawers in Vault.
Contents List
- Series I: Chronological Files, 1630-1778., Extent: 8 boxes. (Box 142-149)
  Arranged chronologically with undated items at the end of the series.
  - 1630 May 31
    - Letter from John Harvey to Sir Robert Heath (Box 142, Folder 1 (Item 1a))
  - 1652 Dec. 6
    - Land patent to Henry Palin & John Swingleton (Box 149, Folder 1 (Item 1))
  - 1660
    - Petition of Thomas Ballard (Box 142, Folder 1 (Item 2))
    - Petition of Edward Harris (Box 142, Folder 1 (Item 3))
    - Petition of Edward Lister (Box 142, Folder 1 (Item 4))
    - Petition of Richard Lymsey (Box 142, Folder 1 (Item 5))
    - Petition of George Boll & John David (Box 142, Folder 1 (Item 6))
    - Petition of John Horsington (Box 142, Folder 1 (Item 7))
  - 1662
    - Petition of Col. Robert Abrahall (Box 142, Folder 1 (Item 8))
  - 1663 Sept. 10
    - Order of the Grand Assembly for the formation of Essex County (Box 142, Folder 1 (Item 9))
  - 1665 Oct. 27
    - Petition of Samuel Ouston (Box 142, Folder 1 (Item 10))
  - 1666
    - March 28 - Writ of Summons of Ira Kirkman (Box 142, Folder 1 (Item 11))
    - June 7 - Writ of Summons of Ira Kirkman (Box 142, Folder 1 (Item 12))
    - Aug. 2 - Writ of Summons of Ira Kirkman (Box 142, Folder 1 (Item 13))
    - Aug. 7 - Writ of Summons of Ira Kirkman (Box 142, Folder 1 (Item 14))
    - Sept. 24 - Writ of Summons of Ira Kirkman (Box 142, Folder 1 (Item 15))
    - Sept. 25 - Writ of Summons of Ira Kirkman (Box 142, Folder 1 (Item 16))
  - 1667
    - March 13 - Land patent to William Dudley (Box 149, Folder 1 (Item 17))
    - Sept. 5 - London Gazette (Box 142, Folder 1 (Item 2))
  - 1668
    - Petition of Anne Molesworth (Box 142, Folder 1 (Item 19))
    - Petition of Peter Garland (Box 142, Folder 1 (Item 20))
  - 1669 Sept. 10
    - Writ of Summons of Richard Norborne (Box 142, Folder 1 (Item 21))
  - 1669/1670
    - March - Writ of Summons of Richard Norborne (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 1))
  - 1670
    - April 4 - Writ of Summons of Richard Norborne (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 2))
    - October 14 - Petition of John Catlett (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 3))
  - 1671
    - November 22 - Petition of Henry Knighton (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 3a))
  - 1672
    - Court Summons of William Berkeley (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 3b))
  - 1673
    - May 24 - Petition of John Mohun (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 4))
    - May 27 - Petition of John Boughen (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 5))
    - Oct. 21 - Petition of Nicholas Wyatt & William Harrison, Jr. (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 6))
    - Oct. 22 - Petition of George Jordan (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 7))
    - Nov. 4 - Land Grant to John Prosser & Thomas Pannell (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 8))
  - 1674
    - Sept. 16 - Petition of Charles Scarburgh, John West, Tabitha Browne, & Edmund Scarburgh (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 9))
    - Oct. 1 - Petition of Elizabeth Peters (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 9a))
    - Oct. 27 - Note signed by Nathaniel Bacon (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 11))
  - 1675
    - June 12 - Certificate of William Narne (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 11a))
    - June 14 - Certificate of Henry Hartwell (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 11b))
    - June 15
      - Petition of Gabriel Hill (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 12))
      - Petition of John Edwards (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 13))
      - Petition of John Edwards (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 14))
      - Petition of Elizabeth Diggs (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 15))
    - June 16
      - Petition of Henry Butts (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 16))
      - Petition of Thomas Bowler (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 17))
      - Petition of Anna Bland (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 18))
      - Petition of Philip Gowen (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 19))
    - June 17
      - Petition of Mary Culpeper (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 20))
      - Petition of John Chilcott & James Hay (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 21))
      - Petition of John Meade (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 22))
      - Petition of James Webb (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 23))
    - June 18
      - Petition of John Edloe (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 24))
      - Petition of William Mosse (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 25))
      - Petition of John Meade (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 26))
      - Petition of Charles Rone (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 27))
      - Petition of Tabitha Browne (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 28))
    - June 19
      - Petition of Robert Beverley (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 29))
      - Petition of Christopher Robinson (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 30))
      - Petition of Thomas George (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 31))
      - Petition of William Rookins (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 32))
      - Petition of Robert Abrahall (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 33))
      - Petition of Richard Young (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 34))
      - Petition of Thomas Pate (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 35))
      - Petition of Mathew Wakeline (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 36))
  - 1676 June 16
    - Account of Richard Hill with William Sherwood (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 37))
  - 1675/1676
    - March 4
      - Petition of William Anderson (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 38))
      - Petition of Maj. Laurence Smith (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 39))
      - Petition of John Johnson (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 40))
      - Petition of Robert Netherland (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 41))
      - Petition of William Kendall (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 42))
    - March 14 - Petition of John West & Charles Scarburgh (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 43))
    - March 18 - Petition of Mary & Robert Hubard (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 44))
    - March 20 - Petition of Richard Ireherne (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 45))
  - 1678
    - Oct. 23 - Appraisal of Christopher Carleton & Richard Walston (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 47))
  - 1679
    - April 15 - Petition of Charles Turner (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 48-1))
    - April 17 - Certificate of William Hartwell (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 48-2))
    - April 29 - Petition of Blissland Parish (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 49))
    - Oct. 2 - Account of Nathaniel Bacon, Jr. (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 49a))
    - Nov. 1 - Answer of the Onondaga Indians (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 50))
    - Dec. 6 - Commission of Thomas, Lord Culpeper (See Oversized Drawer) (Box 142, Folder 2 (Item 51))
  - 1681
    - Jan. - Certificate of Robert Sorrell (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 1))
    - Oct. 29 - Certificate of Christopher Carleton (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 2))
  - 1682
    - Oct. 31 - Certificate of David Wickliffe (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 3))
    - Nov. 4 - Certificate of Benjamin Buckley (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 6))
    - Nov. 6
      - Petition of William Phillips (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 4))
      - Bond of Sarah Yardley (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 7))
    - Nov. 10 - Certificate of Richard Tunstall (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 8))
    - Nov. 11 - Petition of John Story (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 5))
    - Nov. 16 - Petition of Benjamin Buckley (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 9))
    - Nov. 17 - Petition of George Lyddall (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 10))
    - Nov. 22
      - Petition of Edmund Bacon (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 11))
      - Petition of Nathaniel Bacon (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 12))
      - Petition of Edmund Bankes (Box 149, Folder 3 (Item 14))
    - Dec. - Petition of Sarah Yardley (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 13))
    - Dec. 7 - Petition of Moses Davies (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 15))
    - Dec. 16
      - Certificate of Cadwallader Jones (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 16))
      - Petition of Cornelius Dabney (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 17))
    - Dec. 23 - Order of Governor Thomas Culpeper (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 18))
    - n.d.
      - Petition of David Wickleff (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 19))
      - Petition of Lancelot Bathurst (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 20))
  - 1682/1683
    - Jan. 15 - Petition of Daniel White & George Weeden (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 21))
    - Jan. 19 - Deposition of Henry Creyk, Philip Littlepage, & William Tayloe (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 22))
    - Jan. 31 - Petition of Col. Leroy Griffin & Maj. Lewis Burwell (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 23))
    - Feb. 25 - Petition of Sarah Bland (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 24))
    - March 13 - Petition of John Smith (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 25))
  - 1683
    - April 14 - Proclamation of Governor Thomas Culpeper (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 26))
    - Oct. 13 - Instructions of Nicholas Spencer (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 27))
    - Nov. 25 - Petition of Thomas Smith (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 28))
    - n.d.
      - Petitions of Edmund Jenings (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 29))
      - Petition of the Vestry & Churchwardens of Wicomico Parish (Box 142, Folder 3 (Item 30))
      - Petition of the Inhabitants of St. Stephen's Parish (Box 149, Folder 1 (Item 31))
  - 1684
    - April 15 - Petition of Nathaniel Bacon, Peter Butts, George Polegreen, and John Johnson (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 1))
    - April 25 - Petition of John Robinson (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 2))
    - June 23 - Orders from Governor Francis Lord Howard for Capt. William Jones (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 23))
    - July 31 - Proceedings of a Council at Albany, New York with the Sachems of Three Indian Nations (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 2a))
    - Aug. 6 - Letter from the Rappahannock Court (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 3))
    - Aug. 25 - Petition of Henry Spratt (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 4))
    - Oct. 11 - Petition of James Turner (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 5))
    - Oct. 24 - Order of the General Court to fine William Pearman (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 6))
    - Nov. 13
      - Deposition of William Pearman (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 7))
      - Petition of Porter Smith (Box 149, Folder 1(Item 8))
      - Petition of Col. Cadwallader Jones (Box 149, Folder 1(Item 9))
    - Nov. 14
      - Petition of Thomas Chowning (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 10))
      - Petition of George Lee (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 11))
      - Petition of Nicholas Spencer (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 12))
    - Nov. 15 - Petition of Alexander Swan (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 13))
    - Nov. 16 - Petition of Nathaniel Bacon, Esq. (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 14))
    - Nov. 20 - Petition of Charles Turner (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 15))
    - Nov. - Petition of Nicholas Spencer (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 16))
    - n.d.
      - Petition of Alexander Hussey (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 17))
      - Petition of Mathew Wakelin & Anthony Armistead (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 18))
      - Petition of Thomas Ballard (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 19))
      - Petition of Hugh Campbell (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 20))
      - Petition of Edmund Jennings (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 21))
      - Petition of Edmund Jennings (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 22))
      - Orders to Capt. William Jones (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 23))
  - 1684/1685
    - April 15 - Petition of Nathaniel Bacon, Peter Butts, George Polegreen, and John Johnson (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 25))
    - Feb. 6 - Petition of Joune Hunt (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 25))
    - March 5 - Referral of the Justices of the Rappahannock Court (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 26))
  - 1685
    - March 26 - Petition of Robert Keyes (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 27))
    - April 13 - Petition of Christian Loftis (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 28))
    - April 13 - Petition of John Luke (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 29))
    - April 14 - Petition of John Chilton (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 30))
    - April 15 - Petition of Jane Rabley (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 31))
    - April
      - Petition of Barnabi Kearney (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 32))
      - Petition of John & Ann Johnson (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 33))
      - Petition of Walter Bartlett (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 34))
      - Petition of Barnabi Kearney (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 35))
      - Petition of William Millington (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 36))
      - Petition of Isaac Vary (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 37))
      - Petition of Thomas Ballard (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 38))
    - May 6 - Deposition of Governor Francis Lord Howard, Baron of Effingham (Box 142, Folder 4 (Item 39))
  - 1686
    - Proclamation of Governor Francis Lord Howard, Baron of Effingham (Box 149, Folder 1 (Item 1))
  - 1687
    - August 6 - Appeal to the Sachems of the Five Nations (Box 149, Folder 1 (Item 2))
    - August 7 - Answer of the Sachems of the Five Nations (Box 149, Folder 1 (Item 3))
    - November 22 - Bill of Lading of William Wilson & Quintillion Godrick (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 4))
  - 1688
    - April 20
      - Writ of Summons of John Eaton (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 9))
      - Writ of Summons of John Eaton (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 10))
      - Writ of Summons of George Browne (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 11))
    - April 24 - Commission of Capt. Francis Page as Clerk of the House of Burgesses (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 8))
    - April 26 - Speech of Governor Francis Lord Howard, Baron of Effingham (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 9))
    - May 9 - Address of the House of Burgesses to the Governor (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 10))
    - May 10 - Receipt of Governor Francis Lord Howard, Baron of Effingham (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 11))
    - May 11
      - Reply of the House of Burgesses to the Council re. the Committee of Claims (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 12))
      - Address from the House of Burgesses to Governor Francis Lord Howard (Box 149, Folder 1 (Item 13))
    - May 14 - Writ of Summons of William Digges (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 14))
    - June 21 - Writ of Summons of William Anderson (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 14))
    - June 26 - Account of Capt. Simon Rowe (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 16))
    - June 27 - Order of Governor Francis Lord Howard, Baron of Effingham (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 17))
    - July 9 - Warrant for the arrest of Edward Davis, Lionell Dellawafer, & John Hinson for piracy (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 18))
    - July 14 - Bill of John Cutter (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 19))
    - July 19 - Petition of the Vestry of Blissland Parish (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 20))
    - Aug. 1 - Writ of Summons for Sarah Squire (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 21))
    - Sept. 1 - Order of the Vestry of St. Peter's Parish (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 22))
    - Sept. 6 - Proceedings of the General Court (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 23))
    - Sept. 26 - Writ of Summons of Thomas Bott, Sr. (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 24))
    - Oct. 6 - Writ of Summons of William Edwards (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 25))
    - Oct. 8
      - Writ of Summons of William Edwards (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 26))
      - Writ of Summons of William Edwards (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 27))
      - Writ of Summons of William Edwards (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 28))
    - Oct. 9 - Writ of Summons of William Edwards (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 29))
    - Oct. 12 - Proceedings of the Henrico County Court (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 29a))
    - Oct. 13
      - Writ of Summons of William Edwards (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 30))
      - Writ of Summons of William Edwards (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 31))
    - Oct. 18 - Proceedings of Council Meeting (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 32))
    - Oct. 22 - Writ of Summons of William Edwards (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 33))
    - n.d.
      - Receipt of James Crabtree (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 34))
      - Receipt of James Crabtree (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 35))
      - Petition of John Womeck (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 36))
      - Communication from House of Burgesses (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 37))
      - Account of the Sheriff of Middlesex County (Box 142, Folder 5 (Item 38))
  - 1689
    - Jan. 2 - Letter from Governor Francis Lord Howard to the Council (Box 142, Folder 6 (Item 1))
    - Feb. 16 - Receipt of Edmund Jenings (Box 142, Folder 6 (Item 2))
    - March 11
      - Letter from Governor Francis Lord Howard to the Privy Council (Box 142, Folder 6 (Item 3))
      - Letter from Governor Francis Lord Howard to the Committee for Trade and Plantations (Box 142, Folder 6 (Item 4))
    - April 23 - Receipt of Nicholas Spencer (Box 142, Folder 6 (Item 5))
    - April 27 - Orders of the Council to Edmund Jenings (Box 142, Folder 6 (Item 6))
    - April
      - Petition of Walter Whitaker (Box 142, Folder 6 (Item 7))
      - Petition of Edward Davis, Lyenel Delawafer, & John Hinson (Box 142, Folder 6 (Item 8))
    - June 3 - Proceedings of the Charles City County Court (Box 142, Folder 6 (Item 9))
    - July 2 - Deposition of John Dodson (Box 142, Folder 6 (Item 10))
    - Sept. 20
      - Receipt of Col. Wormeley (Box 142, Folder 6 (Item 11))
      - Receipt of Ralph Wormeley (Box 142, Folder 6 (Item 12))
      - Receipt of John Armistead (Box 142, Folder 6 (Item 13))
    - Oct. 19 - Petition of William Anderson (Box 142, Folder 6 (Item 14))
    - Oct. 25 - Proceedings of the General Court (Box 142, Folder 6 (Item 15))
    - Dec. 14 - Account of Clothing (Box 142, Folder 6 (Item 19))
    - n.d.
      - Petition of Thomas Sewell, Jr. (Box 142, Folder 6 (Item 16))
      - Petition of John Swinfield (Box 142, Folder 6 (Item 17))
      - Petition of Bryan & Elizabeth Tarnell (Box 142, Folder 6 (Item 18))
      - Petition of Edward Davis, Lyonell Delawafer, & John Hinson (Box 142, Folder 6 (Item 20))
      - Petition of Peter Proby (Box 142, Folder 6 (Item 21))
      - Account of Edward Davis, Lionel Delawafer, & John Hinson (Box 142, Folder 6 (Item 22))
      - Deposition of William Hilliard (Box 142, Folder 6 (Item 23))
      - Petition of the Chiefs of the Chickahominy Indians to Governor Francis Lord Howard, Baron of Effingham (Box 142, Folder 6 (Item 24))
  - 1689/1690
    - March 8 - Bond of Thomas Preeson (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 1))
  - 1690
    - Jan. 22 - Order of William Edwards (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 37))
    - April 28 - Certificate of John Tucker (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 2))
    - May 13 - Receipt of James Crabtree (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 3))
    - June 4 - Order of the Council (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 4))
    - June 5
      - Petition of Thomas Taylor (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 5))
      - Petition of George Marable (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 6))
    - June 6 - Certificate of Elkanah Pembroke (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 7))
    - June 26
      - Account of Edward Davis, Lionell Delawafer, & John Hinson (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 8))
      - Account of Capt. John Purvis (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 9))
    - July 20 - Account of Ralph Wormeley (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 10))
    - July 24
      - Petition of Sam Weldon (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 11))
      - Petition of Jeanne Clarke (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 12))
      - Petition of William Edwards (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 13))
      - Petition of James Doran (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 14))
    - July 25
      - Petition of Roger Jones (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 15))
      - Account of Edward Davis (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 16))
      - Account of John Hinson (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 17))
      - Account of Lionel Delawafer (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 18))
      - Petition of Edward Ross (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 19))
    - July 26
      - Petition of James Palmer (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 20))
      - Letter from Ralph Wormeley (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 21))
    - July - Petition of John Minson (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 22))
    - Aug. 11 - Order of Lt. Gov. Francis Nicholson (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 23))
    - Aug. 12 - Receipt of James Crabtree (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 24))
    - Aug. 20 - Receipt of James Crabtree (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 24))
    - October 9
      - Proceedings & Deposition of New Kent County Court (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 26))
      - Deposition of Ann Browne, et al. (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 27))
    - Oct. 17 - Order of the General Court (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 28))
    - Oct. 29 - Receipt of Francis Bullant (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 29))
    - Oct. - Petition of Mathew Kempe (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 30))
    - Nov. 17 - Certificate of James Williams (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 31))
    - Nov. 20 - Receipt of James Crabtree (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 32))
    - Nov. 24 - Receipt of James Crabtree (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 33))
    - Nov. 24 - Receipt of James Crabtree (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 33))
    - Nov. - Letter for Francis Effingham to Lt. Gov. Francis Nicholson (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 34))
    - Dec. 12 - Order of Lt. Gov. Francis Nicholson (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 35))
    - Dec. 27 - Certificate of Edward Ross (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 36))
    - n.d.
      - Deposition of Jaob Brittin, Cor Purnell, & Edward Fisher (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 38))
      - Petition of the Householders & Freeholders of St. Steven's Parish (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 38a))
      - Petition of Hugh Davis (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 39))
      - Petition of William Norrington (See Oversized) (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 40))
      - Petition of Alexander Hussey (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 41))
      - Petition of Philip Lightfoot (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 42))
  - 1690/1691
    - Feb. 27
      - Certificate of Thomas Whitehead (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 43))
      - Certificate of Witt Rust (Box 142, Folder 7 (Item 44))
      - Mar. 16 - Account of John Taliaferro (Box 142, Folder 8 (Item 1))
  - 1691
    - Feb. 5 - Petition of Thomas Taylor (Box 142, Folder 8 (Item 2))
    - Feb. 8 - Proceedings of the James City County Court (Box 142, Folder 8 (Item 32))
    - March 9
      - Order of Lt. Governor Francis Nicholson (Box 142, Folder 8 (Item 33))
      - Writ of Summons of Miles Cary (Box 142, Folder 8 (Item 7))
    - March 12 - Writ of Summons of Miles Cary (Box 142, Folder 8 (Item 35))
    - Apr. 9 - Patent of Philip Ludwell (Box 142, Folder 8 (Item 3))
    - Apr. 17 - Proceedings of the General Court (Box 142, Folder 8 (Item 4))
    - Apr. 20 - Account of Edmund Jenings (See Oversized) (Box 142, Folder 8 (Item 4))
    - Apr. 24
      - Proclamation of Lt. Gov. Francis Nicholson (Box 142, Folder 8 (Item 6))
      - Proceedings of the General Court (Box 142, Folder 8 (Item 7))
    - May 1